hey guys this looks like a fun one we
have an equilateral triangle right here
we're given that the area of this
smaller circle is 105 meters squared and
they want us to find the area of the
larger Circle if you want to try this on
your own posit because I'm going to
solve it in three two one so first I'm
thinking since it's an equilateral
triangle we know that each of these
angles is equal to 60 degrees and if we
find the center of these circles and
drop the angle bisector to that point
it's going to cut the 60 degree angle
into two thirty degree angles and next
let's connect this radius from here to
here now let's label it R since it's the
radius of the smaller Circle this side
of the triangle is touching the circle
in one point that means this is part of
the tangent line and at this point of
tangency it meets at right angles to the
radius and now if we focus on this
triangle right here the sum of the
interior angles of any triangle is 180
degrees which leaves us 60 degrees for
the last angle so this right here is a
special right triangle it's a 30 60 90
triangle in every 30 60 90 triangle the
hypotenuse is always twice as long as
the smallest side so if we rotate these
no notes we can match this with the
orientation of this triangle up here so
once again the hypotenuse is twice as
long as the smallest side so for this
one this hypotenuse needs to be twice as
big as this side so this is going to be
2R and we don't need these notes anymore
let's take these two things and copy
them down here so let's focus on the
small circle area let's gray out all
this stuff the area of a circle is pi
times the radius squared well in this
case it's going to be pi r squared so
now we can focus on the largest Circle
so let's create out all of this stuff
there you have the large circle is also
going to be pi times the radius squared
or the radius for this one is 2R let's
get rid of the question mark we can
bring over the pi this 2 is going to get
squared to give us 4 and R is going to
be squared to give us r squared so now
we have pi times 4r squared we can swap
it to be 4 times pi r squared and we
already know that pi r squared is equal
to 105 meters squared so I'm going to
substitute in for this pi r squared 105
meters squared and then 4 times 105 is
420. so the area of this larger circle
is 420 meters squared and that's the
answer to our question we can put a box
around it how exciting